<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

<!-- generator="WordPress/4.8.1" created="2017-09-20 01:13" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>
	<title>PaperWPUI5</title>
	<link>http://localhost:9090/wordpress</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 01:13:26 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>http://localhost:9090/wordpress</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>http://localhost:9090/wordpress</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author><wp:author_id>5</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[solomon]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[sol@gmail.com]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Solomon Akande]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Solomon]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Akande]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>6</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[uchezakari]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[uzakri@gmail.com]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Uche Zakari]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Uche]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Zakari]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>7</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[iLiman]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[ilim@gmail.com]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Liman Mukisi]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Liman]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Mukisi]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>


	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.8.1</generator>

	<item>
		<title>When Life Asks for Everything</title>
		<link>http://localhost:9090/wordpress/hello-world/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 16:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[solomon]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http:/?p=1</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<header id="story-header" class="story-header">
<div id="story-meta" class="story-meta "> I’d like to offer you two models of human development.</div>
</header>
<div class="story-body-supplemental">
<div class="story-body story-body-1">
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="484" data-total-count="540">The first is what you might call The Four Kinds of Happiness. The lowest kind of happiness is material pleasure, having nice food and clothing and a nice house. Then there is achievement, the pleasure we get from earned and recognized success. Third, there is generativity, the pleasure we get from giving back to others. Finally, the highest kind of happiness is moral joy, the glowing satisfaction we get when we have surrendered ourselves to some noble cause or unconditional love.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="540" data-total-count="1080">The second model is Maslow’s famous hierarchy of needs. In this conception, we start out trying to satisfy our physical needs, like hunger or thirst. Once those are satisfied we move up to safety needs, economic and physical security. Once those are satisfied we can move up to belonging and love. Then when those are satisfied we can move up to self-esteem. And when that is satisfied we can move up to the pinnacle of development, self-actualization, which is experiencing autonomy and living in a way that expresses our authentic self.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="459" data-total-count="1539">The big difference between these two schemes is that The Four Kinds of Happiness moves from the self-transcendence individual to the relational and finally to the transcendent and collective. Maslow’s hierarchy of needs, on the other hand, moves from the collective to the relational and, at its peak, to the individual. In one the pinnacle of human existence is in quieting and transcending the self; in the other it is liberating and actualizing the self.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="359" data-total-count="1898">Most religions and moral systems have aimed for self-quieting and, figuring that the great human problem is selfishness. But around the middle of the 20th century, Abraham Maslow, Carl Rogers and others aimed to liberate and enlarge the self. They brought us the self-esteem movement, humanistic psychology, and their thinking is still very influential today.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="412" data-total-count="4591">Rabbi Wolfe Kelman’s life was fraught with every insecurity when he marched with Dr. King in Selma, but, he reported: “We felt connected, in song, to the transcendental, the ineffable. We felt triumph and celebration. We felt that things change for the good and nothing is congealed forever. That was a warming, transcendental spiritual experience. Meaning and purpose and mission were beyond exact words.”</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="353" data-total-count="4944">In one of his many interesting data points, Finkel reports that starting around 1995, both fathers and mothers began spending a lot more time looking after their children. Today, parents spend almost three times more hours in shared parenting than parents in 1975 did. Finkel says this is an extension of the Maslow/Rogers pursuit of self-actualization.</p>

</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-08-14 17:33:01]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-08-14 16:33:01]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[hello-world]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>1</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[A WordPress Commenter]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email><![CDATA[wapuu@wordpress.example]]></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>https://wordpress.org/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP><![CDATA[]]></wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date><![CDATA[2017-08-14 17:33:01]]></wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-08-14 17:33:01]]></wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Hi, this is a comment.
To get started with moderating, editing, and deleting comments, please visit the Comments screen in the dashboard.
Commenter avatars come from <a href="https://gravatar.com">Gravatar</a>.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Real Unknown of Climate Change: Our Behavior</title>
		<link>http://localhost:9090/wordpress/api-goes-wp/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 05:25:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[solomon]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:9090/wordpress/2017/08/18/wp-goes-js-themeuxs/</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="story-continues-1" class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="129" data-total-count="129">As Hurricane Harvey bore down on the Texas coast, few people in that state seemed to understand the nature of the looming danger.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="355" data-total-count="484">The bulletins warned of rain falling in feet, not inches. Experts pleaded with the public to wake up. J. Marshall Shepherd, head of atmospheric sciences at the University of Georgia and a leading voice in American meteorology, <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/marshallshepherd/2017/08/24/four-dangers-of-hurricane-harvey-that-may-not-be-obvious-to-the-public/#6583089e5e17">wrote</a> ahead of the storm that “the most dangerous aspect of this hurricane may be days of rainfall and associated flooding.”</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="43" data-total-count="527">Now we know how events in Texas turned out.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="190" data-total-count="717">Dr. Shepherd and his colleagues have spent their careers issuing a larger warning, one that much of the public still chooses to ignore. I speak, of course, about the risks of climate change.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="302" data-total-count="1972">In Washington, progress on climate change has stalled. The administration has announced its intent to withdraw from the global Paris climate accord. And top Trump appointees insist that the causes of climate change are too uncertain and the scientific forecasts too unreliable to be a basis for action.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="126" data-total-count="2098">This argument might have been halfway plausible 20 years ago – or, if you want to be generous, even 10 years ago. But today?</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="390" data-total-count="2488">Today, salt water is <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/09/04/science/flooding-of-coast-caused-by-global-warming-has-already-begun.html?mcubz=3&amp;_r=0">inundating</a> the coastal towns of the United States, to the point that they are starting to put giant rulers in the intersections so people can tell if it is safe to drive through. The city leaders are also posting “no wake” signs — not on canals but on the streets, to stop trucks from plowing through the water so fast as to send waves crashing into nearby homes.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="263" data-total-count="2751">We all see the giant storms, more threatening than any in our lifetimes — and while scientists are not entirely comfortable yet drawing links between the power of these hurricanes and climate change, many people are coming to their own common-sense conclusions.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="244" data-total-count="2995">As the challenges in the real world worsen, some senior Republicans continue to question the link between human-caused emissions and rising temperatures. Scott Pruitt, the head of the Environmental Protection Agency, said this <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2017/03/09/epa-chief-scott-pruitt.html">on CNBC</a> in March:</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="269" data-total-count="3264">“I think that measuring with precision human activity on the climate is something very challenging to do and there’s tremendous disagreement about the degree of impact, so no, I would not agree that it’s a primary contributor to the global warming that we see.”</p>
Note that he acknowledges the planet is warming. Note that he offers no alternative hypothesis about the cause of that warming — nor will he ever, for the simple reason that there is no plausible alternative. But still, he clings to uncertainty as a reason to do nothing.

To be sure, fair-minded people can and should ask: What are the real uncertainties?

They exist in climate science, and despite claims to the contrary made by climate denialists, nobody hides them. You can spend long days at conferences, as I have, hearing from the scientists themselves about all the error bars of their studies and all the weak points of their computer models.

We are not entirely sure, for instance, how much the planet will warm in response to a given level of emissions. That is a pretty basic question, and the inability of climate science to narrow it down has been one of the great frustrations of the field these past few decades.
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="257" data-total-count="5069"></p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="192" data-total-count="5261">Yet, it is true, the list of uncertainties is still long and vexing. Scientists have trouble, for instance, turning their broad global forecasts into specific predictions for a given locality.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="281" data-total-count="5542">Want to know what the average temperature is going to be in Athens, Ga., in 2050? Wonder how the Asian monsoon, whose rains feed billions, will hold up in the 2070s? Those forecasts exist, but even the scientists who made them are not going to advise you to put much stock in them.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="318" data-total-count="6193"></p>
<p id="story-continues-10" class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="295" data-total-count="6488">The truth is that the single biggest uncertainty in climate science has nothing to do with the physics of the atmosphere, or the stability of the ice, or anything like that. The great uncertainty is, and has always been, how much carbon pollution humans are going to choose to pump into the air.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="272" data-total-count="6760">In fact, calculations have been run on this. If you want, say, a forecast for global temperature in 2100, the uncertainty about how much pollution we will spew out is at least twice as large as any uncertainty about the physical response of the climate to those emissions.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="247" data-total-count="7007">So despite arguments like Mr. Pruitt’s, a century of climate science has brought us to the point where we can say this definitively: We are running enormous risks. We are putting nothing less than the stability of human civilization on the line.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="245" data-total-count="7252">And yet most of us have still not bestirred ourselves to care, much less to march in the streets demanding change. We are like the people in Texas who did not take those flood warnings seriously enough, except that the stakes are so much larger.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="96" data-total-count="7348">Is this failure to act the legacy our generation wants to leave for the generations yet to come?</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>14</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-08-18 06:25:40]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-08-18 05:25:40]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[api-goes-wp]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_old_slug]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[wp-goes-js-themeuxs]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The juju curse that binds trafficked Nigerian women into sex slavery</title>
		<link>http://localhost:9090/wordpress/wp-goes-js-themeuxs-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 05:25:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[uchezakari]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:9090/wordpress/2017/08/18/wp-goes-js-themeuxs-2/</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Traditional west African ‘healers’ and Sicilian psychiatrists are struggling to help free Nigerian women forced into prostitution

Every night as dusk falls in Piazza Gastone in the Noce district of Palermo, a tall, imposing Ghanaian woman dressed in traditional west African robes stands before a small congregation sweating in rows of plastic chairs before her.

The Pentecostal Church of Odasani has been converted from an old garage in a backstreet into a place of worship, albeit one unrecognised by any formal faith group. But what many of the congregation – largely young Nigerian women – have come for tonight is more than prayer; it is freedom.

“Nigerian women come to me for help, they have bad spirits that have been put inside their bodies by people who want to make money from them,” says the self-proclaimed prophetess, as she prepares to start her service.

She gestures to her devotees, who sit nervously fiddling with their phones as they wait for her to begin. “The spirit is forcing them to remain in a life of prostitution. When they come to Europe and realise they can’t live this life, they come to me and I help free them of this juju forever.”

She says she has spent the past 10 years battling the juju curses that are potentially keeping tens of thousands of Nigerian women under the control of human traffickers across Europe.

In 2016 its staff registered more than 11,000 Nigerian women at landing points in Sicily, with more than <a class="u-underline" title="" href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2016/aug/08/trafficking-of-nigerian-women-into-prostitution-in-europe-at-crisis-level" data-link-name="in body link">80% of them victims of trafficking</a> and destined for a life of forced prostitution on street corners and in brothels across Italy and Europe. Before they left Nigeria, many of them will have been made to undergo traditional oath-taking ceremonies involving complicated and frightening rituals often using the women’s blood, hair and clothing. These rituals – which have become known as the “juju” – bond the woman to her trafficker and to any debts she will incur. The rituals make it clear that failure to pay off those debts will result in terrible things happening to the woman and her family.

“This juju might seem like something small or meaningless to people here in Europe, but to the women these curses are real and they are terrifying,” says Princess Inyang Okokon, who runs <a class="u-underline" title="" href="http://piamonlus.blogspot.co.uk/2010/07/piam-english-profile-2011.html" data-link-name="in body link">Piam Onlus</a>, an anti-trafficking NGO and who was herself taken from Nigeria to Italy in 1998. “Using these very old belief systems passed down through generations is a psychological form of control that is much stronger than any violence that can be done to them.”

&nbsp;

“On top of the terrible abuse they have faced while being trafficked, the juju is a constant source of strain on these women, they feel under constant threat and this creates a kind of psychological dependency and addiction,” says Monti. “So when they leave their traffickers, the pressure of the years of carrying this curse on their shoulders can break them.” Casadei says that they recently had a young patient who had been trafficked from her home town in Edo state and had been referred to the hospital after escaping her traffickers.
<figure id="img-2" class="element element-image img--landscape fig--narrow-caption fig--has-shares " data-component="image" data-media-id="17996bcb8afafb7a90f144cfed90481077ee1af5"><figcaption class="caption caption--img caption caption--img"></figcaption></figure>
“She had been doing so well. We were so proud of her. She’d escaped her captors, had been living independently,” Casadei says. “But then one day she received a package in the post from her home town. She couldn’t tell us what was inside but we knew it was related to the juju curse that she’d been made to undergo before her journey to Europe. She had a severe psychotic episode, a very violent reaction to whatever was in that package and we never saw her again.”

Casadei and Monti admit they are at a loss to know how to help the women. “It is pointless trying to say that these curses are not real, these women need to believe in a treatment or solution and there is an impenetrable wall between our two belief systems,” says Casadei. “Our approach of western psychology is virtually useless in these cases.”

Prosecutors say that the juju’s hold over the women is hindering their fight against the traffickers. “Because of the juju, Nigerian women become the perfect victims of sexual slavery,” says Salvatore Vella, a prosecutor in Agrigento. “Gangs know they can trust them, they know women are not going to report them to the police because they are afraid of the consequences for breaking the juju. And this makes our investigation harder. It is almost impossible to find witnesses among Nigerian prostitutes because of the ritual. Maybe one in 20 is ready to speak out. The rest of them are stuck in a wall of silence and fear.’’

There is also evidence of Nigerian criminal gangs in Sicily being in touch with the traditional priests who conduct the rituals. “They are providing the traffickers in <a class="u-underline" href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/italy" data-link-name="auto-linked-tag" data-component="auto-linked-tag">Italy</a> with all the information they need to terrify and control their victims. When the women arrive the traffickers know their names, real ages, names of their relatives, and above all the name of the “priest” who conducted the juju ceremonies. You don’t need to use violence if you have this sort of control.”

Some local African leaders on the island are trying to form a bridge between the authorities and victims to try to break the psychological chains.

Sister Mary Anne Nwiboko, a Catholic nun working in a convent in Carlentini in Syracuse, says she has helped more than 300 Nigerian women escape their traffickers since 1998. A trained counsellor and psychotherapist, she works with the police to help identify and approach potential victims. “I have always battled the juju,” she says. “I do not believe in these ceremonies but I understand the power that they hold over these women.”

In recent months, she says the number of women independently seeking her out to help them escape the juju curses has risen sharply. She says she invites them into her convent and uses prayer and song to try to get them to trust her.

“These women are very far away from their home. I know their language, their world, it helps me explain that they don’t need to be afraid. Behind every one of these ceremonies is money and I try to show this to the women. That this is not magic, it is just a way to keep them under their control.”

The influence of a handful of west African self-styled Pentecostal priests and traditional healers who are claiming to exorcise juju spells is also on the rise.

&nbsp;

The Odasani “priestess” vigorously denies that she is doing anything but using “her power” to save the lives of the women who come to her door.

This evening, after she has started her service, she invites a young woman asking to be freed of her traffickers to stand in the middle of a circle. The congregation starts to chant and pray, their voices getting louder and faster as the ceremony progresses. The priestess blesses water and oil before conducting a traditional ritual of purification, dousing the woman and commanding the bad spirits to leave her forever.

“I ask the spirit, what is your name? And the spirit answers. And I say, in the name of the Lord depart from my daughter,” she says, raising her arms to the sky. “For many when they leave here the juju has departed their bodies. If they believe this then they are healed and they are free. But if they don’t believe then it is no good. If they don’t believe then there is nothing I can do to help them.”]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>15</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-08-18 06:25:51]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-08-18 05:25:51]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[wp-goes-js-themeuxs-2]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Harvey, Irma, Jose … and Noah</title>
		<link>http://localhost:9090/wordpress/harvey-irma-jose-and-noah/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:04:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[iLiman]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:9090/wordpress/?p=42</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="story-body-supplemental">
<div class="story-body story-body-1">
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="66" data-total-count="66">Is there anything we can learn from hurricanes, storms and floods?</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="183" data-total-count="249">People have been asking that question for thousands of years, and telling stories that try to make sense of natural disasters. These flood myths are remarkably similar to one another.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="425" data-total-count="674">A researcher named John D. Morris collected more than 200 of them, from ancient China, India, Native American cultures and beyond. He calculates that in 88 percent of the tales there is a favored family. In 70 percent, they survive the flood in a boat. In 67 percent, the animals are also saved in the boat. In 66 percent, the flood is due to the wickedness of man, and in 57 percent the boat comes to rest on a mountain top.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="311" data-total-count="985">The authors of these myths are trying to make sense of vast and powerful forces. They are trying to figure out what sort of world they live in. Is it a capricious world, where cities are destroyed for no reason? Or perhaps it’s a just but merciless world, where civilizations are wiped out for their iniquity?</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="314" data-total-count="1299">The most famous story, of course, is the biblical story of Noah. As the story begins, the human race is living without law, and as a result is living violently and badly. But there was one righteous man, Noah. God tells Noah to build an ark because He is going to wipe out the rest of humanity with a great deluge.</p>
<p id="story-continues-1" class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="269" data-total-count="1568">What does Noah say when he hears this? Nothing. Abraham protested to God when the city of Sodom was under threat of destruction. Moses protested when God was going to harm the Israelites. But Noah is silent. He doesn’t try to save his neighbors or argue with his God.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="story-continues-2" class="story-interrupter"></div>
<div class="story-body-supplemental">
<div class="story-body story-body-2">
<p id="story-continues-3" class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="272" data-total-count="1840">Rabbis and scholars have often judged Noah harshly for this. “He is incurious, he does not know and does not care what happens to others,” Avivah Gottlieb Zornberg writes. “He suffers from the incapacity to speak meaningfully to God or to his fellow human beings.”</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="356" data-total-count="2196">“Noah was righteous but not a leader,” Rabbi Jonathan Sacks observes. A leader takes responsibility for those around him and at least tries to save the world, even if people are too wicked to actually listen. Moral integrity demands positive action against evil. Noah, by contrast, opts to withdraw from the corrupt world, in order to remain untainted.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="140" data-total-count="2336">Noah and his family get on the ark and Noah gently cares for the animals. Then the rain stops and it is time to go out and remake the earth.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="240" data-total-count="3036">Now God gives Noah a covenant. Moral laws are handed down, and Noah is told to go off and recreate. Noah seems to flee from this responsibility. Perhaps he has survivor’s guilt. He gets drunk. His sons find him lying naked and passed out.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="199" data-total-count="3235">Noah is a good man, but his story is a lesson in the dangers of blind obedience. The God of the Hebrew Bible wants respect for authority and deference to law. But He doesn’t want passive surrender.</p>
<p id="story-continues-4" class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="420" data-total-count="3655">Rabbi Sacks writes, “One of the strangest features of biblical Hebrew is that — despite the fact that the Torah contains 613 commands — there is no word for ‘obey.’ Instead the verb the Torah uses is shema/lishmoa, ‘to listen, hear, attend, understand, internalize, respond.’ So distinctive is this word that, in effect, the King James Bible had to invent an English equivalent, the word, ‘hearken.’”</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="92" data-total-count="3747">Today we live amid many floods. Some, like Harvey or Irma, are natural. Others are man-made.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="289" data-total-count="4036">People are still good at acting individually to tackle problems. Look at how many Houstonians leapt forth to care for their neighbors. But we have trouble with collective action, with building new institutions, or reviving old ones, that are big enough to deal with the biggest challenges.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="273" data-total-count="4309">That’s because we have trouble thinking about authority. Everybody seems to have an outsider mentality. Social distrust is at record highs. Many seem to swerve between cheap, antiestablishment cynicism, on the one hand, and a lemming-like partisan obedience on the other.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="237" data-total-count="4546">The answer is the “hearken” mentality that Sacks describes. This is where Abraham succeeds and Noah fails. Abraham listens deeply to God and derives everything from his identity on down from Him, but pushes out ahead of the shepherd.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="194" data-total-count="4740">To hearken is to be faithful but also responsible, to defer to just authority but also to answer the call of individual conscience, to work within the system but as a courageous, creative force.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="159" data-total-count="4899" data-node-uid="1">Floods are invitations to recreate the world. That only happens successfully when strong individuals are willing to yoke themselves to collective institutions.</p>

</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>42</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-09-20 01:04:19]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-09-20 00:04:19]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[harvey-irma-jose-and-noah]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Facebook Faces a New World as Officials Rein In a Wild Web</title>
		<link>http://localhost:9090/wordpress/facebook-faces-a-new-world-as-officials-rein-in-a-wild-web/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:09:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[uchezakari]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:9090/wordpress/?p=46</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="story-continues-1" class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="100" data-total-count="100">On a muggy, late spring evening, Tuan Pham awoke to the police storming his house in Hanoi, Vietnam.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="259" data-total-count="359">They marched him to a police station and made their demand: Hand over your Facebook password. Mr. Tuan, a computer engineer, had recently written a poem on the social network called “Mother’s Lullaby,” which criticized how the communist country was run.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="90" data-total-count="449">One line read, “One century has passed, we are still poor and hungry, do you ask why?”</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="307" data-total-count="756">Mr. Tuan’s arrest came just weeks after Facebook offered <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/us-facebook-vietnam-idUSKBN17T0A0">a major olive branch</a> to Vietnam’s government. Facebook’s head of global policy management, Monika Bickert, met with a top Vietnamese official in April and pledged to remove information from the social network that violated the country’s laws.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="397" data-total-count="1153">While Facebook said its policies in Vietnam have not changed, and it has a consistent process for governments to report illegal content, the Vietnamese government was specific. The social network, they have said, had agreed to help create a new communications channel with the government to prioritize Hanoi’s requests and remove what the regime considered <a href="http://tuoitrenews.vn/society/40707/facebook-policy-head-vietnamese-minister-discuss-ways-to-curb-toxic-content">inaccurate posts about senior leaders</a>.</p>

<div class="story-body-supplemental">
<div class="story-body story-body-1">
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="376" data-total-count="1529">Populous, developing countries like Vietnam are where the company is looking to add its next billion customers — and to bolster its ad business. Facebook’s promise to Vietnam helped the social media giant placate a government that had called on local companies <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/us-vietnam-google-idUSKBN16N110">not to advertise</a> on foreign sites like Facebook, and it remains a major marketing channel for businesses there.</p>

Corporate behemoths have no values, only quarterly revenue projections. Facebook clearly doesn't care they built the worlds most efficient...</div>
<div id="supplemental-1" class="supplemental first" data-between-flex-ads="true" data-pre-height="1285" data-max-items="2" data-remaining="340" data-minimum="400" data-last-item-height="540" data-flex-ad-adjacency="true" data-post-height="1285">
<div class="supplemental-items" data-supplemental-order="0" data-no-ads="true"><aside class="marginalia comments-marginalia  selected-comment-marginalia" data-marginalia-type="sprinkled" data-skip-to-para-id="">
<div class="comments-view"><article class="comment" data-permid="24117149"></article><article class="comment" data-permid="24117572"><header><time class="comment-time" datetime=""></time></header>
<p class="comment-text">The arrogance that these tech giants display is unbelievable. The assumption that they should have free reign all over the planet is sorely...</p>

</article><article class="comment" data-permid="24117330"><header><time class="comment-time" datetime=""></time></header></article></div>
</aside></div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="story-continues-2" class="story-interrupter"></div>
<div class="story-body-supplemental">
<div class="story-body story-body-2">
<p id="story-continues-3" class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="261" data-total-count="1790">The diplomatic game that unfolded in Vietnam has become increasingly common for Facebook. The internet is Balkanizing, and the world’s largest tech companies have had to dispatch envoys to, in effect, contain the damage such divisions pose to their ambitions.</p>
<p id="story-continues-4" class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="413" data-total-count="2203">The internet has long had a reputation of being an anything-goes place that only a few nations have tried to tame — China in particular. But in recent years, events as varied as the Arab Spring, elections in France and confusion in Indonesia over the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/11/18/technology/fake-news-on-facebook-in-foreign-elections-thats-not-new.html?mcubz=0&amp;_r=0">religion of the country’s president</a> have awakened governments to how they have lost some control over online speech, commerce and politics on their home turf.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="397" data-total-count="2600">Even in the United States, tech giants are facing heightened scrutiny from the government. Facebook <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/09/06/technology/facebook-russian-political-ads.html">recently cooperated with investigators</a> for Robert S. Mueller III, the special counsel investigating Russian interference in the American presidential election. In recent weeks, politicians on the left and the right have also spoken out about the excess power of America’s largest tech companies.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="294" data-total-count="2894">As nations try to grab back power online, a clash is brewing between governments and companies. Some of the biggest companies in the world — Google, Apple, Facebook, Amazon and Alibaba among them — are finding they need to play by an entirely new set of rules on the once-anarchic internet.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="210" data-total-count="3104">And it’s not just one new set of rules. According to a review by The New York Times, more than 50 countries have passed laws over the last five years to gain greater control over how their people use the web.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="293" data-total-count="3397">“Ultimately, it’s a grand power struggle,” said David Reed, an early pioneer of the internet and a former professor at the M.I.T. Media Lab. “Governments started waking up as soon as a significant part of their powers of communication of any sort started being invaded by companies.”</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="108" data-total-count="3505">Facebook encapsulates the reasons for the internet’s fragmentation — and increasingly, its consequences.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="371" data-total-count="5381">Mr. Zuckerberg had wined and dined Chinese politicians, publicly showed off his newly acquired Chinese-language skills — <a href="https://bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2014/10/23/zuckerberg-speaking-chinese-shows-up-at-beijing-forum/">a moment that set the internet abuzz</a> — and talked with a potential Chinese partner about pushing the social network into the market, according to a person familiar with the talks who declined to be named because the discussions were confidential.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="322" data-total-count="5703">At a White House dinner in 2015, Mr. Zuckerberg had even asked the Chinese president, Xi Jinping, whether Mr. Xi might offer a Chinese name for his soon-to-be-born first child — usually a privilege reserved for older relatives, or sometimes a fortune teller. Mr. Xi declined, according to a person briefed on the matter.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="119" data-total-count="5822">But all those efforts flopped, foiling Facebook’s attempts to crack one of the most isolated pockets of the internet.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="234" data-total-count="6056">China has blocked Facebook and Twitter since mid-2009, after an outbreak of ethnic rioting in the western part of the country. In recent years, similar barriers have gone up for Google services and other apps, like Line and Instagram.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="313" data-total-count="6369">Even if Facebook found a way to enter China now, it would not guarantee financial success. Today, the overwhelming majority of Chinese citizens<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/08/10/technology/china-homegrown-internet-companies-rest-of-the-world.html"> use local online services</a> like Qihoo 360 and Sina Weibo. No American-made apps rank among China’s 50 most popular services, according to SAMPi, a market research firm.</p>
<p id="story-continues-6" class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="246" data-total-count="6615">Chinese tech officials said that although many in the government are open to the idea of Facebook releasing products in China, there is resistance among leaders in the standing committee of the country’s Politburo, its top decision-making body.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="388" data-total-count="7003">In 2016, Facebook took tentative steps toward embracing China’s censorship policies. That summer, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/11/22/technology/facebook-censorship-tool-china.html">Facebook developed </a><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/11/22/technology/facebook-censorship-tool-china.html">a tool</a> that could suppress posts in certain geographic areas, The Times reported last year. The idea was that it would help the company get into China by enabling Facebook or a local partner to censor content according to Beijing’s demands. The tool was not deployed.</p>

</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>46</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-09-20 01:09:15]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-09-20 00:09:15]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[facebook-faces-a-new-world-as-officials-rein-in-a-wild-web]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Wild Dogs Sneeze When Ready to Hunt</title>
		<link>http://localhost:9090/wordpress/48-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[solomon]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:9090/wordpress/?p=48</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="story-body-supplemental">
<div class="story-body story-body-1">
<p id="story-continues-1" class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="149" data-total-count="149">When they want to move as a group, meerkats call to each other. Capuchin monkeys trill. Gorillas grunt. Honeybees make what is called a piping sound.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="47" data-total-count="196">African wild dogs sneeze. And that’s a first.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="186" data-total-count="382">No other social animal has been reported to cast a vote, of sorts, by sneezing, although in humans sneezing may once have expressed a negative opinion, as in, “nothing to sneeze at.”</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="272" data-total-count="654">Wild dog sneezing is different. For one thing it seems to indicate a positive reaction to a proposal before a group of dogs. When a pack of these dogs is getting ready to hunt, <a href="http://rspb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/284/1862/20170347">scientists reported Tuesday</a>, the more sneezes, the more likely they are to actually get moving.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="365" data-total-count="1019">Just about all social organisms make group decisions that require reaching a consensus. If monkeys or meerkats are looking for a better place to forage, they need to reach a consensus about moving on among a minimum number of animals — called a quorum, just like in Congress. Even some bacteria do this before <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2001/02/27/science/drug-makers-listen-in-while-bacteria-talk.html">releasing toxins or lighting up with bioluminescence</a>.</p>
<p id="story-continues-2" class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="359" data-total-count="1378">Bacteria use chemical signals but larger animals often use sounds as a way of saying, I’m in. However, among grunts, huffs, piping signals and others, the sneeze had not been reported as one of those signals until a group of American, British and Australian researchers published their observations of African dogs.</p>

</div>
</div>
<div id="story-continues-3" class="story-interrupter"></div>
<div class="story-body-supplemental">
<div class="story-body story-body-2">
<p id="story-continues-4" class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="295" data-total-count="1673">They were studying the dogs where they live in Botswana to see how they decide to go on a hunt. Like most carnivores, the wild dogs sleep a lot. But at some point one of the pack will start what is called a rally, getting all the other members excited and milling around as if they want to play.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="286" data-total-count="1959">Sometimes the rallies are successful, and off the pack goes. Sometimes the pack members lie down and go back to sleep. Neil R. Jordan of the University of New South Wales in Sydney, the senior author of the report, noticed that the successful rallies there seemed to have more sneezing.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="251" data-total-count="2210">Reena H. Walker, then an undergraduate research technician at Brown University, set to work gathering hard data. Dr. Jordan’s perception was right. By far, the best predictor of whether the dogs would actually go on a hunt was the number of sneezes.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="328" data-total-count="2538">Unlike the one-person, one-vote rules of human elections, members of the group were not limited to one sneeze. And if a dominant pack member started a rally, fewer sneezes were needed from the other dogs to get the hunt off the ground, Ms. Walker said, noting that there was some interplay “between dominance and democracy.”</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="417" data-total-count="3213">The sneezing is not the same as a human sneeze. It is a bit like the choo without the aah, an “audible, rapid forced exhalation through the nose” as Ms. Walker put it. And the scientists don’t know if it is voluntary or something that just happens, like a sneeze. So they can’t say it’s a true vote. But they can say that if you want to know if the dogs are going to move, counting sneezes is your best bet.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="255" data-total-count="3468">This is obviously not a parallel to voting on health care. But imagine a group of friends on a beach getting ready to wade into cold water. They talk and stretch and hop up and down, and push and nudge each other, until they either go in or lie back down.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="55" data-total-count="3523" data-node-uid="1">Next time you’re at the beach, see if anyone sneezes.</p>

</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>48</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-09-20 01:10:44]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-09-20 00:10:44]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[48-2]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>How the Internet Kept Humming During 2 Hurricanes</title>
		<link>http://localhost:9090/wordpress/how-the-internet-kept-humming-during-2-hurricanes/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:13:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[iLiman]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:9090/wordpress/?p=50</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="story-body-supplemental">
<div class="story-body story-body-1">
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="315" data-total-count="315">At one node of the industrial backbone that keeps the internet running, employees sheltered from the worst of <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/09/11/us/irma-jacksonville-naples.html">Hurricane Irma</a> in a stairwell of a seven-story building in downtown Miami. When the power had gone out, diesel generators instantly kicked in to keep the lights on and prevent the internet from going down.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="174" data-total-count="489">In Houston, at another of these nodes, called data centers, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/08/28/climate/how-hurricane-harvey-became-so-destructive.html">Hurricane Harvey</a> pushed waters so high that a live fish flopped in a loading dock, but the physical defenses held.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="266" data-total-count="755">Yet another data center, west of Houston, was so well prepared for the storm — with backup generators, bunks and showers — that employees’ displaced family members took up residence and United States marshals used it as a headquarters until the weather passed.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="148" data-total-count="903">“It wasn’t Noah’s ark, but it was darn close,” said Rob Morris, managing partner and co-founder of Skybox, the company that runs the center.</p>
<p id="story-continues-1" class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="460" data-total-count="1363">For all their seeming immateriality, the internet and the cloud rely on a vast industrial infrastructure consisting of data centers linked through a sprawling network of fiber optics. The facilities are stacked with servers — boxlike computers that crunch the data for everything from hospitals, law enforcement agencies and banks to news websites, email and weather reports — that cannot be without electricity and cooling for even a fraction of a second.</p>

<div class="flex-ad-creative">Yet even as millions of people <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/09/11/us/power-fpl-outage-storm.html?mcubz=0">lost power</a> across Florida, and thousands of homes and businesses were flooded out in Miami and Texas, the heavy digital machinery at the heart of the internet and the cloud held firm.</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="story-body-supplemental">
<div class="story-body story-body-2">
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="331" data-total-count="1908">Though the storm disabled some cellphone towers and local connections, Jeff Eassey, a manager for Digital Realty who hunkered down in the Miami building, said the center never stopped processing and transmitting data. It lost utility power around 8:30 a.m. on Sunday, Sept. 10, but supplied its own electricity with the generators.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="324" data-total-count="2232">When the storm eased and he walked outside, Mr. Eassey said, he immediately saw the effect that Digital Realty and other data centers had by keeping the servers going. “Everyone was talking on their phones, searching on their phones, and commerce that uses the internet to do their business was up and running,” he said.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="201" data-total-count="2433">A list of Digital Realty’s top customers shows why those operations are so important: Clients include IBM, Facebook, CenturyLink, Oracle, Yahoo, Morgan Stanley, AT&amp;T and JPMorgan Chase, among others.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="369" data-total-count="2802">Inside the centers, the drill during a natural disaster can be overwhelming. One company, EdgeConneX, lost utility power for three days at a Miami data center, two days at a center in Jacksonville, Fla., and two days at an Atlanta location. But Rich Werner, director of operations at the company, said that backup generators turned on and service was never interrupted.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="181" data-total-count="2983">“Data center operations, to me, is 362 days of boredom,” Mr. Werner said. “And then you get these hurricanes coming through, and it’s three days of pulling your hair out.”</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="144" data-total-count="3127">There are no legal standards for data centers unless they house servers for clients like government agencies, which require special protections.</p>
<p id="story-continues-4" class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="442" data-total-count="3569">But a professional organization, the Seattle-based Uptime Institute, rates the facilities on four tiers of resiliency for events like storms, earthquakes and run-of-the-mill power failures — possibly one reason the internet performed creditably during the hurricanes. The institute’s engineers “go to the site and pull the plug,” said Mark Harris, senior vice president of marketing, “and to be certified, it has to keep running.”</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="505" data-total-count="4470">One necessity is building above the 500-year floodplain, according to Gary Wojtaszek, president of CyrusOne, whose facilities include a data center in the mostly flooded Galleria area of Houston. The water stopped a few feet short of the building, which ran on backup power for several hours, Mr. Wojtaszek said. He added that “practically every single large oil and gas company in the world” operates servers in its data centers — an indication of how commerce of all kind relies on the facilities.</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="388" data-total-count="4858">Depending on local conditions, some centers got off easier than others. In Houston facilities run by Data Foundry, automated systems worked so well that employees pooled resources and watched the Floyd Mayweather-Conor McGregor fight on pay-per-view, said Edward Henigin, the company’s chief technology officer. When everything is working, he said, “what else are they going to do?”</p>
<p class="story-body-text story-content" data-para-count="202" data-total-count="6951" data-node-uid="1"></p>

</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>50</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2017-09-20 01:13:44]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2017-09-20 00:13:44]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[how-the-internet-kept-humming-during-2-hurricanes]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
